There are two types or styles of assessing your data.
数据评估类型或风格分为两种
You can assess it visually and you can assess it programmatically.
可以以目测方式进行评估 也可以以编程方式进行评估
Visual assessment is just opening it and looking through the data in its entirety,
目测评估只是打开并查看所有数据
in Pandas, a text editor or a spreadsheet application for example.
例如 Pandas、文本编辑器或电子表格应用程序中的数据
This is what it looks like in Pandas for this animals.csv file,
这是 Pandas 中一个有着三列内容的 animals.csv 文件
which has three columns; animal,
包括动物、以千克计的体重
body weight in kilograms then brain weight in grams.
和以克计的脑重量
This data set's pretty small,
这个数据集很小
but for larger data sets Pandas will collapse rows and columns.
但是对于较大的数据集 Pandas 会折叠行和列
So in those cases, visual assessment is best
在这些情况下
done in something like Google Sheets for example.
目测评估最好在 Google Sheets 中进行
Programmatic assessment like its name suggests,
正如其名称所示
is anything that uses code to view specific parts of the data,
编程评估是使用代码来查看数据的特定部分
like using functions or methods to summarize the data.
例如使用函数或其它方式汇总数据
Like this dot info method for example.
例如 df.info
You can even plot the data,
甚至可以绘制数据图
but plotting isn't done very often when wrangling.
但在数据整理中 不会经常用到数据图绘制
This is more for exploring during exploratory data analysis,
这更多地用于探索性数据分析
which we'll get into later.
我们稍后会介绍
Regardless of the type of assessment you're using,
无论使用哪种评估类型
assessing data can be broken down into two steps;
数据评估都可以分为两个步骤
detecting an issue and documenting that issue.
即查找问题并记录该问题
This process applies whether you're assessing your data visually or programmatically,
无论是通过目测还是编程方式来评估数据
which are the two types of assessment again.
这一过程都适用
For example, we will visually assess the entirety of this data set in
例如我们目测评估 Pandas 中的这些数据集
Pandas and we detect that Gray wolf is spelt wrong, Gray woof.
发现 Grey Wolf 出现拼写错误 写成了 Grey Woof
Then we document that issue with a bullet point.
然后我们用一个项目符号来记录这个问题
I'd like to separate the issues by quality and tidiness.
我想在记录时按质量和整洁度对问题进行分类
So Gray wolf is spelled wrong, that's our documentation.
因此我们记录为 Grey wolf is spelled wrong (Grey wolf 拼写错误)
This is simply what we see on observation.
记录只是我们通过观察所发现的问题
You don't have to write how to fix it which is part of
不需要写出如何来纠正这个问题
the cleaning step in this data wrangling framework.
因为这是数据整理框架中清理步骤的一部分
So an observation would be,
因此 所谓观察
Gray wolf is spelled wrong as opposed to something like change
就是像 Grey wolf 拼写错误
Gray woof to Gray wolf which would be more of an action item rather than an observation.
而不是将 Grey Woof 改为 Grey Wolf 后者更多地强调一个行动而不是观察结果